Guide to the Gloria Bowen McCoy Papers, 1944-1947 UA.30.01.0086
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gloria Bowen McCoy Papers
1944-1947
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
McCoy, Gloria Lois Bowen
UA.30.01.0086
2.0 Linear Feet
Gloria Bowen McCoy attended Duke University from 1944-1946. The collection includes a scrapbook, class notes, photographs, and memorabilia of her time at Duke.
Biographical / Historical
Gloria Lois Bowen was born June 21, 1926. She attended Duke University in the Woman's College from 1944-1946, leaving after her marriage to John McCoy (alumnus of Duke and Duke Law, class of 1951). While at Duke, she was a member of the Alpha Phi sorority, attended games, events, and dances, and took classes in Music, French, Spanish, Zoology, Philosophy, and other topics.
Gloria and John McCoy had three children, Dana McCoy Anderson, John McCoy Jr., and Carol McCoy Townsend, as well as seven grandchildren. The couple lived in Daytona Beach, Florida and Black Mountain, North Carolina.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Gloria Bowen McCoy Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Related Materials
Kay Brownlee Scrapbooks, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Virginia Passmore Beaujean Scrapbook, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Elizabeth Mapes Horner papers, University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Elizabeth Hatcher and Robert Conner papers, University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of a scrapbook, class notes, memorabilia, photographs, and two personal calendars. The scrapbook includes event programs, namecards, newsclippings, invitations, photographs, documents, a rock, a cigar, matchbooks, corsages, and other mementos from Gloria Bowen's time at Duke. Also included are materials related to Goon Day, including Gloria Bowen's Goon sign, orientation materials, class assignments and notes from several classes (French, Spanish, Music, Philosophy, Zoology, Logic, and some related to parliamentary procedures), photographs of the Woman's College and students, calendars from 1944 and 1946 (the years Gloria Bowen entered and left Duke University) describing social activities, and other materials.
Scrapbooks -- North Carolina -- Durham; Women college students -- North Carolina; McCoy, Gloria Lois Bowen; McCoy, Gloria Lois Bowen; Duke University. Woman’s College -- Students; Duke University -- Football
- Calendar, 1944, 1946 (Box 1)
- Orientation and Goon Day materials, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
- Class notes: Music, French, Spanish, Philosophy, Zoology, etc., 1944-1946 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia, 1945, 1947, undated (Box 1)
- Photographs, circa 1944-1946 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook: Items removed from envelope on back cover, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook: Loose items, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook: Newspaper, 1945 November 21 (Oversize-folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  The Duke Chronicle featuring picture of Peggy Otto (friend of Gloria Bowen McCoy) after selection as beauty queen.
- Loose photographs, circa 1944-1946 (Box 3)
  Includes photographs of classmates from Woman's College, many of them identified, as well as a few views of campus.